[Music]
you're watching The Breakfast Club
morning everybody is dej envy Angela Yee
Charlamagne tha God we are The Breakfast
Club we got a special guest in the
building the multi-talented
hi guys it is so interesting to watch a
man to just continue to grow man as
people that be talking to us like we
don't know Amanda's eels kids in general
like like you're new to him you think
Instagram is causing a big big oh no
resurgence but yeah I mean two days ago
was the anniversary of my Caitlyn Jenner
moment that was two years ago no that
was no two days ago though yeah that was
like the one-year anniversary and I know
some people might be like how you got a
one-year anniversary but like people yes
somebody on Twitter was like oh that was
that was a year ago but that changed my
life
so because after that happened it went
from like oh you want a TV show to like
thank you sister Thank You Queen you
know and it went from like oh you just
somebody who be talking to like oh when
you're in real spaces where things need
to be said you'll say it that's amazing
cuz I we've known you for so long I
don't look at it as like wow that
changed Amanda's life because I look at
it as like this has always been amazing
always well my mom who is West Indian
and therefore does not acknowledge
anything here excellence when it
happened I was like yo like I'm going
viral like you know this is like a thing
and she was like I don't really know
about all that you know and was really
trying to downplay it until we were in
the mall and we were in an Apple store
and three people came up to us and it
was a white chick a straight black guy
and a gay black guy and they all came up
and we're like thank you so much for
what you said thank you so much for what
you said thank you sis for what you said
and my mom was like
I don't people know I have to go watch
the clip I'm like it's kind of Sunday
but no I think um it was really cool too
because I think a lot of people in
Hollywood got to see like offer it that
I'm a real one and you know not
everybody everyone it's tough to balance
that tough to balance real and it's
tough to balance funny it's tough to
balance Interlake Interlake no I mean
I'm just that's me but they do it
authentically doe like you can go to you
and you can get commentary about social
issues sexism things going on in the
world but then just if you just feel
like [ __ ] around me and funny you can
do that to everybody can't do that so
it's a good balance of ratchetness and
righteousness righteousness ratchetness
and righteousness yeah I mean I like who
knew that the video of me saying that
Roseanne Barr you know the media me
singing like you know you got that wrong
Monday I didn't know that would go viral
and that ended up becoming a whole song
people are like putting on a ringtone
the idea agent stuff ever hit you like
could you pull back a little bit
no they'd be like anybody can tell a man
they pull back one no no I mean if you
wanna get cursed out sure definitely
cursed out and it's something I think
that you feel like it's productive or
it's coming from a good place
yeah at least take it into consideration
nobody should be scared to know
something and I have like people around
me that know me so I and that I trust so
like I know that if they're bringing
some of my attention they're not doing
it for any other reason than because
they genuinely have a good intention for
myself no I'm not stubborn like that I
mean I'm really a best idea wins kind of
person cuz you know we all have emotions
and whatnot so sometimes you really do
like get in the emotions of things and
I've been really working on thinking
things through and taking out emotion
etc etc so it's like sometimes you need
someone to be like a EAA
but I don't I don't think it's about
holding back as much as just like
learning how to temper things in the
right audience you know like you don't
got a fine you don't got to find a
different way to be you just got to find
different versions of real have you ever
been surprised by what somebody's been
offended by that you said like yes
because that some chick this morning I
was looking at my comments about the
Caitlyn Jenner situation and I had
mentioned to Caitlyn Jenner in that
conversation how in the 70s you know
there was a number of black households
that were on welfare and that they had
made like this stipulation that if a man
lived in the house that you could not
get government assistance and so I felt
I feel like that has also created a
chasm because a lot of women felt like I
well you gotta go in order for me to get
this assistance even if you know they're
trying to build a family and this woman
was like you know I'm just incredibly
disappointed all-caps and disappointed
just all caps italicized disappointed
that you would continue this narrative
because it's really not what it is and
it's like I mean I'm not I'm not shading
you the facts are shading you like this
is what I didn't make the rule it's just
what it is I mean this is a reality you
have you ever seen the movie Claudine
like get into it listen I did the rail
yesterday and I was on this my refer I
said white people and a woman saying you
don't want nobody to use the n-word but
you calling us white people you are
white people are we tweeted it I was
like uses the term Mandy cracker-ass
cracker uses mayonnaise uses colonizers
and i mean i think that you know for
folks to have a problem with that it's
like do you have a problem with reality
like that's my problem with the whole
argument of like trying to equate what
we say about white people to what we say
about black people like the histories
are not the same the situations are not
the same as the false equivalency don't
ever say to me like we'll stop saying
[ __ ] if you want white people to stop
saying it because i don't base my
blackness upon the spectrum of what
white people can do the two are two
different things if you are a black
person and you don't want to
you don't want black people to say [ __ ]
make it about the fact that you have an
issue with the word and you know what it
represents but don't ever tell me about
why I should not do something based on
whether white people can do it if you
don't want them to use it you shouldn't
say it I'm like that's two separate
issues you know and I think that we've
just been so colonized you know that we
really in a real way think that white
approval is the standard for what should
get done or what shouldn't be done and
it's like that's why I create it smart
funny and black because we've had so
many negative images of black culture
we've seen so much in our schools of
just like being taught about our
identities and our history like in a
very kind of asterisk kind of way it's
like by the way slavery by the way
Martin Luther King and then don't you're
not even gonna learn about Malcolm X
unless you like have a black parent or
somebody that's like teaching you so I
create a smartphone in black because I
was like not we need to we need to have
a celebratory space for black culture
and also like we need to have a space
where we can talk about black culture
through a comedic lens in a real way and
you're on tour right now you go and told
you like thirty first we go on tour July
30th through August 14th ten cities and
it's like it's a dream no we finished oh
we air August we are air argos 12th yeah
no we finished I mean this is my baby
like it gonna be nice on tour while the
show is also back right towards the end
of it the show I was playing it wasn't
honestly it's just the way things land I
mean to be honest like the beautiful
thing is to be able to be on a show like
insecure but also have my own entity and
I think a lot of folks like when they
get a shot they forget about their own
stuff you know and it's like no the shot
is to help propel and continue to
motivate your own stuff like because
I've been able to be on and secure and
is only legitimized you know my
messaging it's only you know giving me
peace of mind in terms of money so that
I can like focus on the creativity and
with smart funny in black it's not just
like a live show with the band and folks
being on stage being funny it has a
purpose I want you to learn while you
laughing and so you know I I just really
always tell people like don't ever work
harder for somebody else in you gonna
work for yourself
like that's always
the thing that I see people do in my mom
our parents that have done that forever
like you know they work on what can work
and work and then they be looking at you
like oh you like like your job are you
like that's how it's supposed to be I'm
like no that's how it's gonna be smart
funny and black I've said it a million
times that's the best game show that's
not on television it don't need to be on
television um I sold it and then I took
it back and I sold it again
and I took it back because I realized
that the value of the show would be
diminished by putting it in a space
where people are in control of it that
don't care about its value or about what
it can do for the people there's other
projects that I'll sell but with smart
funny and black I realized that this is
really a show that needs to be built up
from the ground up with the people you
know like we are going to crowdfund
eventually but like doing these tours
and y'all coming out and buying tickets
in these cities and selling these shows
out and getting merch which you can get
right now at smart funny on black on
backslash bookstore um and as you can
see by the shirt she has on his yeah we
got duvet covers we got blankets we got
pins we got shirts we got mugs we got
whatever you need you know your whole
house could just be like smart funny and
black man I did I had an exact telling
me that they [ __ ] it up they [ __ ] up
smart funny and black and exact told me
that an exact was like I'm to be honest
we trying to make a smart funny in white
room and it's like the show has already
been in existence for over a year at the
time like we've been doing it every
month it's the most turnkey project ever
just put us on a stage
Mike put the mics I mean put the cameras
get the audience let's go and they were
like but like we're like are there white
people and here's the tea when I first
created it it was like no it's smart
funny and black as the content you don't
have to be black to be on the show but I
have since gotten over that like why
can't we just have an authentically
black space I agree like I don't see
anything wrong with that and I think
that it's really important because I
feel like right now a lot of people's
energy is going into like we need to we
need to fight the outside forces fight
the outside forces and I think that's
important but in a multi-pronged
approach to change I think you need to
have different of different energies
going in different directions
and my thing is we need to not
necessarily from from my work is not to
necessarily be fighting the outside
forces but like building up our inside
forces like we need to be enriching each
other you know and I think we put so
much energy into trying to fight with
like folks that don't give it they don't
give a damn about black people they
don't even really care about white
people they care about money you know
like they don't even know what they care
about so a smart funny and broad smart
and smart funny smart and funny like
what about that nah nah nah I have a
master's in african-american studies I
get to put it to use every night that we
do this show and it's all about you know
creating a place for folks to come
through and laugh and get get excited
about black history back coach and black
experience and you can be any race
ethnicity gender class to come to this
show you just gotta know your place you
can come and learn or laugh you know you
gonna find out about WTB Dubois and you
also gonna find out about you know what
floor did homeboy I'm right and really
live on there you go you know so pit
floor mm-hmm do you believe in the
institution of marriage the reason I
asked that is the Jason Mitchell was
here and Jason Mitchell say he doesn't
believe in the institution of marriage I
don't even know who that is
okay let me just say this and this is no
shade to him I think we have reached a
point now where first of all we keep
calling free speech we keep calling just
people having an opinion free speech
which is not what free speech is free
speech means that you can say what you
want and the government cannot impede
otherwise free speech is really just you
talking on your ass okay so there's that
but we've we like misnomer it free
speech to mean like free access because
really everybody can have an opinion now
like and then have a platform to say it
but y'all not everybody is a thought
leader like not everybody's opinion is
valid like not everybody's opinion as
educated or has married just cuz folks
say something doesn't mean you have to
give it like credence you know so like
Jason Mitchell if he's gonna talk to me
about acting well he's gonna talk to me
about you know parts on you know that
he's played he can talk to me about
things that he has research
I am all here to listen and have
interest but like I don't really care
about his opinion on marriage like he's
a young man right isn't he like 20
nothing I mean I'm not saying that like
he's wrong but I'm just saying like his
opinion doesn't inform my trying to
marry him I believe in the institution
of marriage in the terms of when it's
for the reasons that you want and I say
that because for some people it really
is a contract break on our taxes I know
I make sure if something happens I'm
taking care of this to you I know that
I'm getting everything to me and we have
a kid together I mean when I kiss it
whatever the reason is there's your
reason yeah if you choose not to that's
your I just don't think that marriage is
what defines whether you have succeeded
or accomplished and that's the thing for
a lot of women it's like if I don't get
married I didn't I didn't do what I was
supposed to do out here you know I I
mean I feel like that's in my trajectory
but that's just because I feel like
that's part of my story at some point
maybe I'll feel differently but you know
it could happen it couldn't happen it
doesn't mean that you didn't have a
great life and you're not a complete
person and I've been to weddings where
I'm just like why is this like this
[Laughter]
alright somebody tweeted out Easter raid
teases season three insecure will be
about black masculinity a topic I bet
she thinks she's an expert on who
tweeted this so follow the trend of
other prominent black women producers
directors writers in filmmaking and
promote some sort of every about black
men and J Ellis responded you know but
what do you think about that what did
they say he said as a black man it was a
part of the first two seasons of Easter
ray and the very diverse writing staff
of in Secours work I'd have to say shut
the [ __ ] up I mean that's really bout
the bottom line like it's it's toxic
masculinity I mean I had somebody on my
Instagram that yesterday say like there
is a mole
meant against black men against straight
black men and I'm like there have
definitely been movements against
straight black men but it ain't from
black women hey especially not right now
I think the movement if anything is to
try to push straight black men into
growing up and into stepping into a new
space of acceptance of their own selves
and of emotion and of going to therapy
so that they're not consistently in you
know it's not even post-traumatic stress
syndrome disorder
it's like current traumatic stress
disorder B's being a black man in this
country you know so that they're not
dealing with survivor's remorse for like
winning in the midst of like a bunch of
dudes who haven't been able to like we
just read my new book already I know a
lot of black women are really involved
in wellness in a way that we never have
been before like wellness is a huge
movement in black in the black women
community and I don't think it's reached
over that far into the black male
community in the same way and so we are
we are getting ahead you know a lot of
women have been telling me recently they
had PTSD because of relationships
they've had hell yeah yes Mars is going
through a really awful divorce and she's
talking about how she has PTSD she had
to go to therapy and everything for her
situation we can hit on to something
well he basically was cheating on her
moved out I was living with a whole
nother woman won't give her a divorce
and she's having an awful time trying to
deal with it they have kids together and
he's not keeping up with his end of the
bargain and it completely caught her
off-guard it's just like folks decide
they're the how do I put it I feel like
there really has to be something to be
said for like being a man of your word
or a person of your word and I feel like
too many brothers like that doesn't
apply to what they connect with women on
it's like they will stick to that when
it comes to their barber when it comes
it's true like they'll say that when it
comes to money you know I'm saying like
yo like if I if I told you I'm a pay you
wanna pay you and they demand it back
but when it comes to that with women
like yeah I said that we're committed
and I'm not gonna cheat on you it's like
but
like though but man and sometimes I
gotta just grow up and get out of this
phase and I haven't cheated since
October 2016 I'm done the fact that you
can name the date with the faithful mill
community I really like that because
it's like it's like making faithfulness
cool and it's for black folks like we
need that like that's what smart money
in black is really on like we're gonna
make education and being learning and
being about this beauty and blackness
cool not that it's not but like just
completely trying to elevate that so I
love that y'all do that because there's
and this isn't no way to say that there
aren't like women who are shady
like I feel like whenever I as a woman
talk about this on my Instagram like men
are always like what about women and I'm
like I don't date women I'm not in the
vagina business stop expecting but I
just think that there's there it really
is such a pushback from men a lot of
black men on women who simply want to be
holding them accountable and want to
empower them and instead of like meeting
the challenge it's looked at like you're
trying to like put me down it's like nah
I'm trying to show you like yo you could
be this like right I was gonna say but
just along those lines I was gonna say a
lot of men also act like you have a
problem if you don't forgive them and
try to help them work on themselves
because you the option to stay or leave
if I decide to stay and work through it
I can't if I decide to leave you can't
fought me because you messed up and I
left you got to decide are you baking
you got to decide are you investing or
are you sacrificing mm-hmm
you don't want to talk about because
when I talk to students in school
sometimes to stories that I talk about I
talk about my story grow up coming up I
took my Charlemagne story because it's a
[ __ ] up story
[Laughter]
story you know yeah because I've seen it
I've seen it up close and personal and
the fact that you know you never gave up
but you always kept that smile on your
face so to see the success talk about
that as far as that grind because what
you put into this industry a lot of
people don't see they only see they're
insecure now that's true wax without
they're talking about yo I thought you
just talked hella [ __ ] I didn't know
that you was like doing math [ __ ] you
got like wax you literally came to my
show at Caroline's that was sold out and
I did an hour and a half lakh Hillen
yeah you were there he's like yo my bad
what the hell man - sealed wormhole one
day like with he turn he goes a man -
fine as hell but yo who want to wake up
to this every morning that is that if
I'm with you you're waking up to head
every people have such a misperception
about like what you put out like I'll
have people hung my on my Instagram all
day like oh you know you don't you you
don't have a manager than that and it's
like I have suitors all year long and
I'm like no no no you know so that's not
that's not it - the grind because it
actually correlates with the personal
life because I really do believe that
like I will meet somebody so it kind of
continues to drive me in a positive way
to continue to be hopeful and give
people opportunities etc with the grind
I've always believed like in my actual
talent I always knew my worth but you
have to know your market value and so
people don't understand the difference
between that and that's how you get in
the way of like advancing but you known
for a long time like
I've always been like talented I mean
because you start a Sirius radio and
before that but think about everything
she taught it in college she went this
seriously she was she did she didn't go
to college and go to Nickelodeon I never
gave up because I had so many people
around me also that never would let me
give up you were one of those people you
were one of those people I met
Charlemagne later but at the end of the
day it's like he's like you have become
those people in this phase of my life
where like you'll be like yo keep I did
not want to put my bends on my on my
Instagram because I was like I don't
want to look Flossie I don't want to
look like I'm trying to stunts on people
I don't want to be holding up at the end
of imaginary players day was that a 4.0
4.6 like I didn't want to be that person
right but then main was like you have to
put it up because you got that being
your complete self like you got that
without without having to forsake any of
your integrity and you need to be able
to show people that you can get what you
want whether it's material or not by
sticking to your guns and so I think
that's one of the main issues and also
there was a certain point where it was
just like what you know I have a degree
but I don't have a desire to do anything
else I've always known that this was the
space I needed to be in I just needed to
find my way to it like for all intents
and purposes smart funny black is my
first hit you know like I've been
creating stuff like even like but we all
knew that it was gonna pop off you still
having pop-pop it's gonna pop I think
medical pop pop well you you somehow
have to remember that like its
development so that when you do pop
you're ready you're ready it's like I
know like right now like by the time we
did smart funny in black I already know
how to write in my comedy style so I can
write a smart funny in black I can write
a whole two hour show
in an hour I already know I used to be
an artist I have music like you can go
on YouTube and see my music videos etc
so with the band I know how to lead a
band I know how to tell the band you
know what key to be going etc etc like
and then I also do production I used to
do hella productions I mean
damn near all of them so I know how to
handle myself on stage excetera etc but
sometimes we get frustrated on the path
and to your point people give up because
they're like damn why shouldn't turning
over yet and it's like it's I think a
lot of that too is like people think
that they're owed the turnover like
they're like I put in the work like why
hasn't it happen and that's when you
have to really really step back and I
we've talked about this before here like
I went to therapy and I had to really
step back and say like okay what are the
ways that I'm getting in my own way and
I think that you know there's a certain
state miss that I had that was
unintentional and I think there's a
certain level of like frustration that
gets put out there because you're just
like why am I having to like explain
these things and it's really not trying
to be at anybody it's just your own
internal work you know caring itself out
but the reason I say it's so important
to know your market value versus like
your own personal value is because
that's what drives you crazy right when
you know what you're worth but it's like
homeboy your friend Kanye is these
[ __ ] better than me like you really
feel that way like it's all these folks
out here winning and you like what am I
doing wrong and you have to really look
at yourself and be like well I know when
I first got to LA I had to really
remember like I had to really take a
look at like what is the value of the
work I've done I've done a lot of stuff
but nothing had real like poignant
like market value it was valuable to me
you know but it didn't have enough value
in terms of like credits for agents
etcetera etcetera and these things that
people think you know that map these
things that do matter and so what was
great about becoming a part of the cast
have been secured was that legitimized
it was what was a credit that was
legitimate to like other people you know
and you need that but you have to
understand like that that's part of the
game and a lot of times get we get bent
out of shape and we quit because we
don't understand the game and we don't
understand the difference between
knowing your worth but also knowing that
there's like other value to other
projects and that you got to get in
certain spaces to increase other
people's perception of your work and if
you don't have personally just kind of
yeah this is the game then work is
different from from how we grew up Dukas
wharf is it dollar musty now avoid
followers and like
than retweets I remember dropping you
off years ago to your crib in Harlem and
you was like there's nothing worse than
being broken famous it is so irritating
but do then they don't care cuz they got
only follow me that's not I mean I feel
like that's when influence is really
important like what are you doing with
that you know I feel like this is an
interesting time where you're on this
internet and you have so many eyeballs I
mean I don't have nearly enough like
nearly the amount of followers as like a
number of my peers in terms of like the
millions you know who are like Instagram
influencers etc follow Adam and until
the man sales men sale but I have a
following there is active and I think
it's super dope like when I say like hey
let's raise money for these young women
to go on a trip to the Dominican
Republic people like put that over the
top within 5 hours when I say like hey
look I really am big on like giving
money to young women traveling our young
people traveling that's like a very big
platform for me and it's just dope to
see that my following I call it you know
it's the ratchet hoes
I mean it's sorry that's not a threat to
has it's the responsible I'm sorry I
looked at waxing my following is like
you know we know our 401k you know
saying we have a form okay we know our
credit we get you know annual pap smears
like when we hear Cash Money taken over
for the nine nine thousands like we know
what's about to happen we waking you up
ahead in the morning you know the
responsible house and it's um Kanye he
posted about you he tweeted about you
you know Charlamagne told Kanye what's
the front row center when I did that
poetry gym in 2001 like if you watch it
on YouTube like he's sitting right there
like and you know I hope it's a picture
you Kanye John Legend and yep from when
I was doing in TV
I mean that the whole it's so funny
because it's a very interesting time
right now lines are being drawn I think
people are really showing they're
showing themselves and they're showing
what is valuable to them and you know I
think it's interesting how like we have
absolute
we really been very specific about like
who we choose to criticize about their
allegiance with 45 and who we choose to
let slide and when it comes to black
women I feel like we have been
completely like hard-line about it you
know but when it came to this guy I
don't know if it's because he does good
songs or you like his sneakers or what
it's like folks were very easy to simply
just be like well you know it's not that
bad you know it's not it's not it's not
that D she's trying to express himself
and have freedom of speech dangerous
it's dangerous and we when we undermine
the level of danger that is associated
with someone like Kanye West openly
supporting forty five and then his wife
openly you know supporting and literally
being on camera and saying like Oh Kanye
legitimized him like you have to
acknowledge that and when I see my peers
and people I know that are just like
what's fine let's just go to I oming and
like just live it up and dance it up it
says to me like okay if you're a
journalist and you had to go there for
work I can respect that but if you went
there to be cool you know and you went
there because you have somehow had done
the mental gymnastics in your head to
make it okay you are literally on a path
of just being a part of the problem you
are part of the problem and I stand by
that and I know you gonna counter so
what's that you got a job to do your job
like every name they don't like talking
to Donald Trump and all the number
that's their job
so if you're a journalist and you don't
know for that reason I agree yes but
we're seeing the music business that we
are in like it's in a new era right now
you know you see these label cats I've
been there for twenty years and like
this is a new era like hey you know and
I'm like it's coming up it's coming on
yeah because you're no longer just an
artist like you are an individual that
has more than your music to market and
to you know connect you to people etc so
with that being said we have to
acknowledge also that like for a long
time the music business and we all know
this has been like this secret society
you know like me two hits the music
business Amy
just go start it hasn't hit already it's
coming it's because the mindfuck has
already started to take place of like no
you can't say it because it's against
you know the black man and you know it's
gonna put people down I mean that's what
they tried to do with the Russell thing
you know but at the end of the day it's
like when you start hearing people like
police start speaking out you know and
you start hearing people like myself
speaking out I haven't even said my
stories you know you you know all of it
I mean Reese got it so I left the other
day and was like Reese Reese is the
artist that was on producer first album
santino say about a story to them he
said I was dead I was like but you can't
bring that up on camera sir oh okay okay
well tell me after yes he said I was
there yeah and I did nothing a moment of
a guy being trash you got to share with
the room guys right here you was sitting
right there I'll tell you okay you would
say I was in a situation right hmm you
would put me in the situation oh my god
but not in a bad way like you had the
best of intentions right no no you had
the best of intentions and send it down
there you had the best of intentions but
to your defense it was so normal for
this person to speak to me in that way
then it didn't even rattle you it was
you and an of your homeboy and it was
just like and and I remember having to
do the mind work with myself like this
is not okay hey I know that it seems
like it's okay by the surroundings but
no I was in a meeting I don't I can't
explain the situation if you want I
didn't know I don't feel like okay God
sir yes do you see what you see what
just happened because I don't feel like
dealing with
gonna have to deal with all these women
don't see that's why we don't say [ __ ]
cuz I don't want to have to deal with it
and now we have these internets and
[ __ ] get on the Internet's and they're
little Internet thugs come behind and be
like he don't want to [ __ ] you die
you're just like you know what I should
have just kept it to myself and gone to
therapy so we Envy had brought me into a
meeting for a job and while we were at
the meeting the individual was talking
to me and he was saying that I should
change my name so that was most of the
meeting like him being like nah you
shouldn't be a man to Deva I'm Anna
Devane cool nobodies don't listen to you
I'm like but people are already
listening to me whatever and then and
then I made it I made a reference to
like how the industry changes etc and
somehow or another we got on the topic
of people like sleeping their way into
positions and it wasn't about me like it
was about like a specific incident and
this person who is an executive that is
interviewing me to hire me for a job was
like well when you gonna [ __ ] me right
next to him like this and I know cuz
y'all have to know like MV has been a
brother like MV has looked out like I
remember in one of those moments of the
grind being too much I always tell the
story of like I was on Twitter just like
lamenting an MP called me and was like
what stop like stop crying stop acting
like you don't know what to do and
create some opportunities for yourself
and you like gave me a blueprint and
even though like I wasn't able to turn
those opportunities into like big things
it gave me hope and hope as a whole
other currency that you can ride you
know but he told me Pumas yeah I mean he
essentially was like you have value have
stuff that is worth something so like
put it to work like that's what you know
that's something that a lot of us don't
realize a lot of times I've managed to
put all of my stuff to work so I haven't
had to [ __ ] anybody to get into a
position you know what I mean like now
that we have some art funding in black
it's like I designed this logo so I put
my art to work you know I designed the
logo we have merch for sale you know so
you can get the merch it's like but I
know how to do merch because I had to
paint tote bags
make money and I had to like you know
try and scrounge up a little money a
little couple of dollars here to get
some t-shirts to sell you know a
Grenadier you know and then like my
website shout-out to WordPress for
building my website for smart funny and
black and the website like I had to
design the aesthetic for the website you
know DJ I use the DJ I still DJ which is
why I'm able to know every song so I can
like put that in the show so you know
it's like I've been fortunate but it
doesn't matter and I say all that to say
like it don't even matter how talented
you are like me two hits everybody like
it's just that individual be tagging me
that individual will be Amanda SEALs in
me and I'll bet you money he don't
remember seeing that shit's Ray said
it's so damn I said that so much I mean
I've seen him say it on camera
we all have yeah but we all said it on a
TV show to another individual he just
told her I heard you [ __ ] your way to
the top why would you say that to
somebody you know like and that's the
thing like it just got it's just gotten
it's gonna be real it's gonna be crazy
how I mean I've had I've had like a
rapper literally like say to me I was
like hey I'm in town um you know would
love to link up and I think maybe I was
naive cuz I really just thought we have
working relationship snowboard and this
person's response to me was I want to
see your [ __ ] show me with your finger
oh geez well we're not hooking up now I
mean I mean I do show somebody a [ __ ]
with you that's what I'm always right is
it you're spread like what is it is it a
photo of the finger
delicate situation because a lot of
times for women like we might want to
connect and politic with people in a way
but you can't even ask for somebody's
information because they think that
you're trying to highlight they're gonna
try to holler at you so sometimes you're
like man I really want to talk to this
person about potential opportunities but
I can't because I don't want to make it
seem this way and then oh guys are gonna
be like oh she's trying to F and you're
like I'm not really trying to do that
I'm trying to do the same thing y'all do
that pilot is just trying to collaborate
if I'm trying to [ __ ] you gonna know
right okay like it's not gonna be like
some surreptitious you know like you got
to figure out the rhythm no it's gonna
be a very clear distinct movement
there's a picture of Charlemagne sitting
on Wendy Williams lap that's
inappropriate that's an appropriate you
know I also this is Quincy Jones asked
me to you know
ah 28 when I win win do you and I
thought I had to be like 20 yes he was
like come on sit on my lap and I had
told him that I love bass lines so
that's like my favorite part of the song
and so when I sat on his lap he went in
my ear so between what Calise yeah and
Kanye producing the whole AB are you
listening the NAS is album Friday no
it's not even about you know if a man
does not listen in on eyes you know that
serious like my man is nas is the
subject of the third portion the my
master's thesis was in three parts and
it was a thesis on the after the rap
album as a continuation of the Africa
American narrative and Nas was a huge
part of that because the first part was
you know just explaining the second part
was I broke down Biggie's life after
death record by record in comparison to
native son and the third part was I
interviewed a number of individuals who
I considered to be hip-hop you know
experts from Beverly Bhansali etc and
everyone kept saying if you're gonna do
this and talk about the narrative you
have to talk about knives he's one of
the greatest MCS storytellers of all
time you know so he was a huge part of
that he has a blurb on the back of my
poetry book you know when I'm serious
and knives had some type of dinner do
you remember this and I was not allowed
to go you were invited and then
uninvited uninvited and I was uninvited
because I guess you know I'm not even
doing this today but no I mean I just
feel like there's so much stuff that
goes on and it's just unfortunate like
how much you just have to keep to
yourself to protect people who don't
have any shame you know but like y'all
know like I've really mmm I've had like
I warm up when I'm going onstage like my
diction you know warmer upper is uh I
never brag how are you like keep it
because it's the best secret I rock
Yvette's prestigious Cuban link flooded
Jesus and the legs watching Kathie Lee
and Regis my actions are one with the
seats I can do the whole thing like that
and we all know that one of the greatest
verses of all time is through the lights
cameras and action grandmas and golden
folder scroll plan season on deceased
but in the Beast arise like he said call
copies leaving savages roaming the
streets live on the run police carry my
gun check my eyes I'm with the system
that imprison my son smoke a gold leaf a
hawk heat nonchalantly I'm raunchy but
things that it was really never haunts
me wow funny style [ __ ] rollin the
power rooster heads profile on a bus to
reconcile all the wheat inside a [ __ ]
with them eyes on the pretty things in
life props is a tube that was life is
like a cycle [ __ ] come home someone go
in do a bullet come back and do the same
[ __ ] again from the womb to the tomb I
presume that unpredictable then solute
life rapidly that's the ritual but he
was beating his wife so I can't listen
to the album damn we came with an
allegation even if I just I'm not here
for it and I know that it's not okay for
women to hit men it is not okay but I
think it's also beyond that like I mean
there is just a
lie in that unita wyoming picture there
was a lot of things it was a Wyoming
picture there was that interview and
there's my own experiences you know and
you just combine everything and you're
like I'm just as hypocritical as the
individuals in Wyoming I'm just as
hypocritical as the individuals
listening to our Kelly where I've
somehow disassociated this person's
music with them even though I know even
though I've had like personal exchanges
with them that show the the fact that
they're not you know a value but you
know what happens is it's like the music
that you heard from them before you knew
that that still fits with you because
that that's associated with them in a
different way that's associated with
your nostalgia with your your growth you
know what I'm saying but like the new
[ __ ] I think that's for me what it is
like I can't I definitely can't listen
to no new stuff you know I mean like I'm
not gonna lie to you and tell you that
like if verbal intercourse comes on that
I'm gonna switch the song no but I'm
absolutely notic waiting you know nas to
someone who is like urinating on young
women either yeah I mean it's almost
impossible to not be a 1000% I mean I
talk about that in my upcoming book
small doses which is based on my podcast
by the same name small doses um it's
hard cuz now hasn't said anything about
all of this either we don't we don't
write in the music though I mean it's
not like nas is a talker outside of the
music you may in the music Touche but
like I said it's not just that
yeah I'm saying it's like these are
things that you know it's just doing the
math you know you and then you just grow
up you know I'm just grown and there's a
certain things that you have to just
like remove from your space and cleanse
and it's not even like a shade thing as
much as much as it's just like it
doesn't have the same value anymore that
it did and you know you have records
that are part of your upbringing but
that doesn't mean that you have to still
be a fan of the person and you know of
the artist and I think that's my biggest
issue with our Kelly it's like people
still want to be fans of art Kelly thank
you know like they're not even just like
I just like the music even though he
trashed they still be like no like he a
good musician like he's like a pair of
those women are willingly their age
their adults they've decided
twelve playing all that in hindsight
I'ma be honest with you it's not it's
like six great records on then
everything else is trash Philip but I
will say six great because you have to
because it ends up being a part of the
whole conversation because people in
Evatt ibly will be like Oh what about
Chris Brown you know what I mean like
then you just start naming like folks
and being like well what about them what
about them and it's like there's also a
spectrum some people are like wrong is
wrong and I'm like no stealing um lip
gloss from Target is wrong it is not the
same as shooting up a target that is
also wrong like we can't act like
there's not a spectrum and create these
like false equivalencies like get out of
here you know I mean somebody like some
unknown person wearing a mag a hat it's
but that's a black person that's wrong
Kanye wearing a mega hat that's another
level of wrong there's more you know
with great power comes great
responsibility all of that like get out
of here you know so I just I I love the
music but I don't I can't support at
this point like there's just too much
you just shouldn't you know too much you
know and I always cancel coach or work
and somebody be uncounseled why not yeah
yeah yeah okay why not people can be on
cancer but the thing is is that no
nobody want to do to work people just
want to be like I said sorry can I come
back and it's like we just have a very
very deep and rich history of black
people in this country being oppressed
and then choosing oppression and a lot
of us would rather replace the rather
replace the oppressor then no longer be
oppressed like it's almost like we want
to have the power to oppress it's like
that's not that's not the the move and I
think that when it comes to being
uncanny like are you actively like
showing that you have changed your tune
or did you just change your tune because
that got uncomfortable over there cuz
that's not yeah you have to really show
change you show that okay I know I
messed up and I'm making efforts and
making and taking steps to figuring out
what I need to do moving forward no one
wants to be a hunted if you would just
say like listen I took the Gua
yeah I'd be like I took the money we
have to also know that people do make
mistakes in life and we have to know
that we make mistakes right and beyond
cancer no no you ready a long time ago
but you know about that and I think they
you know it's it's a very unique
experience being a black person in this
country because when you see black
people in other countries that are
fighting it's there in their country you
know like I'll say like when I saw Black
Panther and I saw them fighting on Black
Panther I'm like no white man is
watching no but then I had to remember
like nah but they in their country and
if you're in proximity there's gonna be
disagreements that may lead to fighting
that's why when people talk about black
on black crime I'm like right you know
especially when the fact that there's
been so much gentrification that you put
even more black people on top of each
other you expect humans to not interact
but we are doing that in a unique way
because we're doing that under the guise
of a white oppressor and so it makes it
seem like we're not supposed to act like
you know natural humans would and have
conflicts because then if we do it then
it looks like we're like less then we're
supposed to be and that's just a false
concept people say please boot Elliott
well y'all black people killing each
other well we live next door to each
other and [ __ ] got hot fake you know and
killing everybody else they know black
mass shooters like that you know so I
think that um you can get uncancelled I
think it's important to have cancer
culture and I think it's important to
have challenged culture because I think
it's important that we hold each other
accountable and it really upsets me when
we act like holding black people
accountable accountable is somehow
helping out white oppression and I'm
like yo I don't measure my ethics based
on the ethics of a race that was
literally created to oppress other
people like that whole notion is just
twisted like the quote-unquote white
race was created to make it okay to go
over an entire globe and rape and
pillage and demean and dimin
and obliterate people so why would I
base my ethics on anything going on over
there no in the black community you look
at the Jewish community they've got
their own ambulances because they own
everything like we should be having our
own infrastructure of how we deal with
things of how we handle business etc and
we did have that and then integration
came and it splintered that and I think
we need to get closer to getting back to
that concept in some cases they just
grate up destroyed it Ivan black Wall
Street and everything you're saying is
absolutely correct but all somebody
gonna do is get on line and say oh hush
you're biracial you don't know what
you're talking about and that is false
[Laughter]
like I don't know when light-skinned
meant by ratio like look at Envy he is
bright as hell bananas just found out
he's from Africa did you do ancestry yes
you didn't know which is what but the
reality is like you know that is part of
like to somehow diminish like my
blackness by my light-skinned and not
even know how I got there like that's
just also a part of like part of black
history in America is that there's gonna
be light skinned black people like there
was slavery and there was all types of
interference and attempts to you know
diminish us so I don't know that concept
is so foolhardy I can't understand it
- for the life of me and also we've had
so many like incredible leaders across
the spectrum of melanin that it just
seems stupid to somehow make it like I'm
not value ap Angela Davis Malcolm X like
then list goes on and on and on and on
so but DJ oh they love to be like you
blonde you got blonde hair so you ain't
really down for the movement well we
appreciate you sharing your intellect
thank you for coming through my
intellect
this morning so I would like to I came
here for this so it's not
in black we're going on tour the
situation one-on-one tour July 30th
through August 14th you can go to smart
funny and black comm for tickets we are
going from LA to Philly New York Detroit
Chicago st. Louis Atlanta New Orleans
Dallas and Houston we're coming to your
town all of those off the top of your
head that's the routing you got to know
your [ __ ] we are coming to your town
come and rock with us we're also gonna
be doing free master classes in certain
cities because my opinion black is also
about education and we want you to come
and you know I'll go get your merch so
you can come through and rep so you can
go to smart funny black comm go to our
bookstore and if you listen to me and
being like I don't even know what you
talking about you can go to youtube
Amanda SEALs or go to smart funny and
black calm and go to videos and you can
check out what the show is and just know
that this is a show that is for the
people it's about the people and we do
it by any joke necessary all right
Breakfast Club good morning
[Music]